What we call the neural crest, it forms during the closure of the neural tube.
The skin reflects the quality of cerebrospinal fluid.
My neural tube here is a neural plate.
At some point above, I have amniotic fluid.
Then, it will form what we call a neural groove.
That is to say, here, outside and inside, we
will say here,
I have amniotic fluid and so, inside, I have amniotic fluid.
This means that my first amniotic fluid represents the fluid
of primitive cerebrospinal fluid.
So, at some point, the fluid present here, in my neural tube,
comes from the same origin as the tissue that is here.
Cerebrospinal fluid is an expression, on a vibrational level,
of what happens here.
At other moments,
Treating the skin is about rebalancing the entire cerebrospinal fluid system,
all these drainage spaces.
We studied them with absorption areas,
manufacturing areas, and pressure balance.
So the skin translates the balance of reciprocal tensions of the
membranes that are expressed in this system and in all this lymphatic system.
The skin is the basic expression.
The foundational expression of the deep metabolic balance of this nervous system
with respect to cerebrospinal fluid.
Initially, it was the same.
We can say that the skin represents the internal quality
of the depth of your body.
In a way, it represents a state of metabolic balance
where any imbalance can manifest on the skin as vital imbalances.
Vitamin imbalances, mineral imbalances, and more specifically in the areas integrated
with the neural crest.
At the moment I have this formation, I have laterally the first
neural crests
that will appear and migrate throughout the body, including the face,
including your digestive system, and that will form your entire peripheral
nervous system, so large that it becomes a tissue.
But we will study it at the facial level.
and we will study it at the level of the viscera and it also represents a state regarding the appendages.
First coloration, tanned, is an increase in melanin. Be careful if
you are
overexposed. If it is a brown color, it may indicate a state of imbalance
called Addison's disease. If it's a yellow color, it may
represent a liver or biliary lesion. The black skin may express a deep disorder at the pancreatic level.
If you have skin that is straw-colored, there is a suspicion of a possible future cancer developing.
It is also influenced endocrinologically.
Pregnancy hormones accentuate the color of certain tissues like the nipples, for example.
Hypothyroidism leads to a disturbance in melanin.
Pituitary and adrenal hormones also act on melanin.
One more thing.
Importantly, this metabolic relationship, the thyroid in a very
simplistic way is rarely ill by itself; it operates in tandem with the
adrenals. In other words, the thyroid has
a very important metabolic action to oxygenate the body but
into
all cells it participates in oxygenation and oxidation
of the system.
On the contrary, the adrenal removes the toxins
It detoxifies because it plays a role with cortisol.
At the thyroid level, you have T3, T4.
T3 is a hormone that doesn’t function until it’s transformed into T4 to be
functional and help oxygenate the body.
What allows this change?
Among other things, it's the adrenal.
So cortisol allows the conversion of T3 into T4.
If I now have too much stress, there is an increase in cortisol in my body.
I have a decrease in my thyroid activity
because it does not know how to transform my T3 into T4
since it inhibits the conversion of T3 to T4.
So to have a good conversion of T3 to T4,
I must have a balance regarding cortisol levels.
Too much cortisol, I cannot transform my T3 into T4
and at the same time, it removes, it cleans the body
so stress destabilizes your adrenals
but will primarily destabilize
deep oxygenation because it does not allow the transformation of T3 to T4
that facilitates oxygen integration at the cellular depth.
But the thyroid, it is self-dependent in its function.
So if it doesn't know how to nourish itself with oxygen, hence the effect of this feedback loop.
At the same time, I remind you that you have hormonal connections.
The hypothalamus is what links the nervous system and
the system...
hormonal, which has a direct influence
on the pituitary gland.
And the pituitary releases hormones
for the thyroid. So how do I have all these
feedback loops that need to be understood? A hypothyroidism
or hyperthyroidism. Someone
who comes with problems, I am cold,
I feel chilly, the lesion
is somewhat bulging, I gain weight, etc.
Very often, it's the adrenals
that are empty. And I remind you
that the adrenals not only produce
hormones
such as cortisol, but also minerals, cortico-minerals.
But also everything for the nervous system.
For example, a large part of your neurotransmitters,
adrenaline or acetylcholine, are produced by your adrenal glands.
Congestive spaces can be reactive spaces, if you will.
The importance of having functional adrenals
and that many of our problems stem from having depleted our adrenals.
The adrenals work with radicals.
And that works with the genital system.
At first, in an embryo, the adrenals are huge.
They are much, much larger.
Later, they will not grow as quickly, but they have significant growth.
People who have recurrent rhinitis, colds, migraines, etc.,
may have stasis up there, so it’s up to us to relieve all that.
Or stasis at the diaphragmatic level, the recesses that stop neuro-pulmonary,
which will hinder the proper movement of your diaphragms and thus prevent proper mobility.
What about? Your adrenals that are completely dependent on your diaphragmatic movement
on a lymphatic, venous, arterial, and even cardiac level.
For example, people who have a red color around a collar,
like this, can indicate dysfunction at the thyroid level.
I have a very red face.
I remind you that you have an embryonic type liver, an endodermal type
and you have a mesodermal type liver.
That is to say, you have a portal liver, a vascular liver, and a
digestive type liver and that the liver is a meeting of the two. So you can have
a portal type liver
with people who have a very red face, portal hypertension which
may actually be
a manifestation of the spleen in relation to your left adrenal. You have a very important dynamic
between the heart, liver, spleen, and
small intestine, that is, the mesenteric system.
This is a sponge for blood, this is a sponge for blood, this is a sponge for blood, this is a sponge for blood.
The liver is dependent on this functioning, particularly with the spleen and my small intestine.
The main connection is my portal vein here, which comes here,
which connects to the lateral part of my small epiploon,
which is a double vessel-carrying membrane that maintains this information.
So if now I have my adrenal, which rises,
it has been shown that in splenomegalies, in hyper-dilated spleens,
I can end up with a congested liver, because I have a system here, and sometimes even with
hemorrhoids.
In fact, it's a disturbance of the entire fluid context of the system.
The response is a hyper-loaded liver.
The resulting clinical response is a wholly red face.
So, the red color tightens a thyroid collar.
On the face, portal hypertension, or excess ferritin storage at the liver level.
You also have...
locally or in patches, which appears like this, what we call histamine excesses
or excess vitamin B2. Then you have another color that may
appear, it is a color that is a bit dull, gray, light brown, representing
deposits
of melanin reflecting the physiological balance of the blood situation. You
also have what we
call a blue type color, especially on the face, which can indicate an imbalance.
Cardiovascular at the nail level, at the lip level, at the
skin level
which shows an oxygen absorption deficit in the body. So if you
have small venous dilatations that appear if you find them here
it may indicate a potential portal imbalance; if you find them on the face it may indicate a pulmonary imbalance seeking oxygen as
in fact, any scar can cause a facial stop, so it’s essential to work on
the tissues to free the
adhesions. Swellings
could also have a hepatic or renal origin depending on the
location. Under the bags here at
the eyes, it may indicate a decrease in renal function.
If you have associated ascites,
it indicates a liver problem.
You have the whole context
of renin, angiotensin
in this system that can
indicate a problem, this time,
renal. So ensure you consider
the heart, kidney, liver.
But also, look where the lymphatic and diaphragmatic locations are.
People with oily skin may express an imbalance,
particularly in women, in estrogenic transformation.
That is, do not forget that there is a part of the hepatic area
that transforms into hormones metabolically
to form the quality of your estrogens.
Hence the need for chocolate to sometimes have good...
hormones. What happens regarding bilirubin? The thickness
of the skin may
reflect a hormonal imbalance. People with very thin skin should consider seeing
the heart. What is happening in the mediastinum? What is happening in the system? How
can I relieve the heart? Remember that the heart is supported by its fascia
pericardium, vertebral, sternopericardial, vertebropericardial, phrenic-pericardial, in a closed system
that supports the heart's motility. The electricity of the heart
does not sustain it alone; it needs a facial environment, thick, hormonal issues and especially
thyroid or hypothyroid type disorder.